

## **CONTACT ME**

L

+66 96704 8618



ankur.kapoor84@gmail.com



Bangkok, Thailand



https://www.linkedin.com/in/ankur-kapoor-b1699019/

# AREAS OF EXPERTISE

## **Key Skills**

Service Strategy, Service Operation, Stakeholder Management, Capex & Opex Optimization, Service Design, Service Transition, Business Development, Project Governance

## **Functional**

Catalog, CRM, Ordering System, Charging & Billing, 5G Monetization

# **Tools & Frameworks**

JIRA, Sonar, Sigma, Ginger, Jenkins, Smart AMT, Function Point, eTOM, Grafana, Kibana

## **Technology**

Microservices, Cloud, IoT, Big Data & Hadoop, Kafka, Kubernetes, PostgreSQL

# **AWARDS**

**Employee of the Year 2015** At Amdocs Manila, Philippines

# **ANKUR KAPOOR**

# **DIRECTOR - SERVICE DELIVERY PRINCIPAL**

Experienced Principal with a demonstrated history of working in the telecommunications industry. Skilled in Production Management, Business Support Systems (BSS), IT Infrastructure Management, Telco and Management. Strong operations professional with Masters in Business Administration focused in Information Technology Management

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

## **SERVICE DELIERY PRINCIPAL**

Amdocs Thailand · Bangkok · Feb, 2022 - Present

Leading 5 managers covering DevOps, Support, SRE, Operation and FTCR with over 30 team members. Manage the overall operations program scope and maintain continuous alignment with strategic business objectives, set program plan, set priorities, and resolve conflicts, secure budget, and timelines

# SOFTWARE ENGINEERING MANAGER

Amdocs Thailand • Bangkok • May, 2019 – Jan, 2022

Onsite technical manager for all Digital and Post paid Billing Applications. Led successfully Fast Track CR Team for delivering 20+ projects within 2 years

# **CONSULTING MANAGER**

Amdocs India & Philippines • Manila-Pune • Jan, 2015 – May, 2019

Complete responsibility/accountability for solution management for major/
transformation/Fast-Track releases including conflict resolution and prioritization of
activities across different phases of the project

# **SENIOR BUSINESS ANALYST**

Amdocs India & Philippines • Dec, 2011 – Jan, 2015

Pre-Sales & Scoping activities such as presenting Product Demonstrations, defining and writing Statement of Work (SOW). working on Business Requirement matrix, Revenue Realization matrix, RFPs/ RFQs, Effort Estimation

## **BUSINESS ANALYST/ SOFTWARE DEVELOPER**

Multiple • India, Malaysia • Aug, 2006 - Dec, 2011

## **EDUCATION**

Masters in Business Administration (Information Technology) S P Jain Center of Management (Dubai - Singapore), 2010 - 2011

Bachelor of Engineering (Computer Science)
MAIT, IP University, New Delhi, 2002 - 2006